i might be tidying up this cave but in
other ways it's getting a whole lot more
messy
the chest monster is slowly growing
however i have been working on a bit of
retexturing
for this cave base the cave of
contraptions so in today's episode i
really want to get down to work on
making more of this a bit more pretty
and i've came to realize that it's kind
of like the worst time to be working on
a cave there's a new update on the
horizon for minecraft and it's literally
the cave update and there's so many cool
blocks especially around vegetation
that would make caves
a lot nicer to live in so i've got to
say that af
you built this one in the wrong update
so i have been working on texturing but
i can't quite figure out
zf storage system
i i don't really understand
is i have to go i think all the way to
the bottom
just to get stuff it's not particularly
wait no
how does this i really don't know how
this works oh unless it sends shulker
boxes all the way to the top see this is
it this is so confusing it also looks
like he's got every single block except
andesite which is the one i want so
while i've been thinking about how i'm
gonna retexture this entire cave i have
received a message from some of the
secret base bros over at cleo corrales
base which walked into a wall and they
said it's time for more shenanigans and
i need some points for what i've already
done so that's where we're going to
start off today's episode by going over
to cleo corrales base i don't know who
it belongs to at the moment and we're
going to do some more shenanigans
also
there is an auction
for these properties right here
and my goodness i want this one
actually i kind of want all of them but
particularly i want this one we're gonna
pop down
17 diamond blocks hopefully i can win
this lovely i believe it's like new york
style it's definitely sort of american
skyscraper i absolutely love the design
and you know why i want this because it
means that i don't have to build a barge
hq i would transform this
into the barge headquarters if i win it
of course if if i don't then i'll uh
i'll have to build something but anyway
we need to head over to corrales base
and i've completely forgotten which
direction it is doesn't look like
anything else has been stolen by the
sewer bros oh look here they are
amazing timing and why is b dubs blonde
and is everybody blonde at the moment
now this is this is just wrong
this is this is not right
b dubs like impulse and i've been
waiting we saw you like i don't know
what if you're going to try and pretend
like that's been there the whole time
because we literally watched you just
like we watched you build it i just
moved it over a block it was down here
it's been down here for a while
you guys really need to explain this
blonde hair situation b-dubs told me i
wasn't gonna be cool
unless i dyed my hair blonde oh cool so
it's peer pressure everyone's dying
their hair blonde because appearance
yeah
yeah i mean green look what color is
your hair uh
mousy brown
i would say a beautiful sandy blonde
you're setting trends man
everybody wants to get up with the times
yeah i feel like there's a trend though
oh missing
oh we should shave a g in the back you
want a jean to build your hair the back
of my head is a pristine waffle and i
won't hear a word against it
it's true yeah
yeah okay it's okay okay so i've done
something to cleo's base it was a trap
and i didn't get the reaction i wanted
or i was expecting but i got a reaction
so i want i want some points and i want
to know what you guys have done and we
should dish out some points well we know
what you did yeah because i gotta watch
you build it yeah yeah see here i got
this uh forklift here there were two
forklifts the chances of him finding out
that one is gone
very slim or cleo finding out for that
matter right definitely won't find out
what's the bar we just five points
easy ten ten points
let's split it
seven points eight points seven
either way seven point eight
we gotta agree green okay eight eight
points eight points eight points
a clip of the reaction i got from cleo's
video what can i say that no what no no
what
i made cleo laugh so that is part of the
thing
and i want some points for it yes we've
deliberated we've seen the clip i say 10
points
i'd i agree with that
yeah all right
good job right let's go with what have
you done
well okay i've actually been working
quite hard on mud and i think it might
be best to just show you so
we're gonna have to do a cut because we
can't just leave here okay and uh i'm
gonna show you firsthand what i've been
up to yeah this is it you like it what
have you done oh uh yeah so this this
bdubs should recognize this it used to
belong to him right now
oh that's right yeah i flipped it i
flipped the whole mansion it used to be
the right half and i flipped it to be
the left half
that's a lot of effort there's a lot of
effort for
okay well
i would be really surprised if she
noticed this because i didn't notice and
i built this
this is my mansion
12 points i'd give you 15 but you didn't
finish it's not done yet i will finish
though because i don't want i don't want
anybody to get mad then i tore it down
so it's going to go back into it exactly
the way it was but just flipped i can't
oh i honestly can't believe you've done
this are these points going to stick
you think this will never get no i mean
if this this is a high risk
there's a there's a good chance this is
coming off the board okay okay so new
rule numeral or
i need to clarify something because
obviously us showing uh this in the
video they're just gonna go hey cleo
they swapped the mansion round don't say
it so so
we just wait for cleo's next episode if
she hasn't noticed in her next episode
then the points lock in right so that
way we're always one step ahead from the
viewers spoiling our lovely shenanigans
the points stand thus green 10.5 scar is
on one i don't know where scott is he's
doing his own thing impulse 16 in the
lead and b dubs with a staggering nine
points
staggering staggering staggering okay
very nice do you guys i i'm up for a nap
in another thing i don't mind
i'm up for it i just need to finish that
interior do you want to group steal
something because i mean
let's group steal yes
take a risk dudes
i want to put the lighthouse in the
sewers no you don't i do i do i think
it's not gonna fit is it maybe not the
whole thing maybe half okay would be a
great centerpiece i know right as i
really i really really want the
lighthouse in here
oh my gosh
half let's say half let's go let's go
nab it i really want it ever since we
built this thing i really want the
lighthouse in here
[Music]
guys
i mean hey gee if you capture him and
keep him down here
oh
30 points extra because he's he's surely
from the surface you can't you can't
capture an enderman i know your game
guys how is he not moving excuse me
[Laughter]
[Music]
he wants that dirt block that's what's
up
oh good
feed him
eat it this is the worst thing
no no no no no no no no no
you're nudging him out of my vision
oh right right right
i've never seen this before
this is
what is happening
he's very angry oh man
oh can we name him are we gonna keep him
we should
we should keep him all right i'm not i'm
not a creative person so i'm just gonna
go with ender bro ender bro works for me
it really works like the lighthouse is
like properly in the the oohs
which is i think it's cool
honestly i don't think i could take it
if if clio notices in in her next
episode because uh
i mean putting that there with uh three
three of us was was a lot of work so i
really don't want to put it back but
we'll see i think it's a pretty high
risk for that high risk that's a very
high risk yeah how did the points divvy
for them
20 points overall 21 points overall
divided by three
i like that nine points each
yeah
yeah yeah we got it we gotta wait for it
we gotta see if it sticks first i don't
see how she doesn't notice at the top of
it's missing but okay
we'll just hope for the best i suppose
okay so this is what we'll see if the
points stick from here and then we'll
ramp things up and hopefully scar and
wren will get in on the whole sewer
thing as well and get some points under
their belt while we're in the area we
might as well do something that i have
been kind of putting off but it's the
last day so i have to do it and that is
exuma's base
race so he has an elytra course that
goes around his base and some people
have been putting up their times okay i
now know the course so this is for the
real thing timed and here we go so when
you're doing an electric course and
flying in general
there's basically a top speed i can't go
any faster than when i immediately right
click a rocket and i think a rocket
lasts about three seconds
so the key is to get as quick corners as
possible while maintaining this same
speed and not hitting any block because
that will slow my momentum i probably
don't know the map as well as i think i
do i've only done a couple of laps on it
but i think i can make this through
pretty quickly
and up and then straight down now going
down you will travel faster than a
rocket and done
okay i have no idea what my final time
was there because um i'm not a magician
i can't count while i'm going so i'm
gonna have to put this into editing and
see how long it is uh i totally did not
see that i had to pay for this okay so i
did a practice run and i did a timed run
i got a total of 43 seconds and 46
milliseconds
to the dot
oh my goodness
that is
just below tang oh my goodness there's
less than 10 milliseconds between me and
tango that's not a very secure victory
so i think what i'm gonna do is i'm
going to do one more just to kind of see
if i can get a little bit bigger of a
gap
and i'm going to try really hard this
time instead of just talking through it
i was kind of casually trying to teach
people how to do electric courses
because i i think i think i need
more time between it
now there's absolutely no rules here
from what i can tell the game begins
when you pass jump off the starting area
touching the ground or landing
disqualifies you the game ends when you
land back inside where you are now the
rings must be flown in order yes okay
cool it doesn't say that you can't do
this from what i can tell so i'm going
to start off by flying through and
starting my time to run right now
so the key is to keep up
with as much of the rings you got to hit
all the rings
and
get tight corners
oh that was close
i don't even know if there's a prize for
this thing
and down
and in now i don't know what the time is
i was kind of focusing couldn't time
that myself so i'm going to have to
check what the time is in editing of
course you know what it is it's on
screen right now look you can see it i
can't all right i'm going to go and do
that now
so i need to update mine to green i
spelt that horror
you know what
that's
that's my
that's my new name grain sounds like a
breakfast cereal okay i got this time
around 43 seconds
milliseconds that is a bit more of a gap
between my score and two of the closest
people which is corrales and tango so
that
is good i only did a couple of runs and
i think i'll leave it at that if if
those guys want to come back and try and
beat it then be my guest so i give them
an opportunity to come back and give
that a go but i feel like i kind of
nailed that almost first time it took me
a little it took me a little while to
actually learn the course
because it's not the most intuitive
thing in the world you have to learn it
basically but that was a bit of fun i've
been itching for a bit of an elytra
course for a while so now let's head
back to our base where we're gonna do a
little bit of sprucing up in the cave
and
we'll discuss
the method that i think i have to get
back
the green mansion
so i've got a plan to get my base
back in my possession and i have also
been working on zf's base just slightly
improving you can see that there's a lot
more cobblestone than there used to be
but i want to do a little bit more oh
that's going to be a problem but i i
need to delay actually swapping the
bases back i have a good way of doing it
and i can't exactly tell you because it
will kind of ruin the surprise
however i want to delay swapping back
just a little bit longer just a couple
of days and the reason if i can show you
in my old base
i said i've just left the timing
couldn't be more perfect look
i don't know if let's see if you notice
anything is there anything strange
happening
in this area
no
maybe there's something strange
happening here
look
the man is tidying up my mess
i i can't believe it there's there is no
more the chest monster's gone this is
the most exciting thing but the thing
he's not finished tidying up so here's
the plan we just we delay things a
couple days we let zeder finish tidying
up the base and then we swap back
dastardly
so we're back instead of space and while
we're waiting for the big swap while
he's while he's finishing tidying up my
base i think we should make a few more
improvements to zetas base i also have
no idea what happened to the door i
haven't touched it i don't have a bow to
be able to open this so i genuinely have
no idea what's happened there it just
opened i came in one day and it was open
don't know what's going on however we
are going to continue making some
improvements to zf's base there's a bit
of a trade-off i think if he tidies up
my base i can tidy up his with a bit
more building so let's hop into a time
lapse and get some work done
[Music]
so this is what i've done i've added
some skylights but they're not really
skylights they're just fake holes with
uh some lanterns in and then it's got
some vines coming down and what i've
tried to do is add a bit of color like
i've added some grass patches and some
mushrooms to try and break up the
monotony that is all of the gray blocks
so i've tried to add some texture and
some focal points to kind of help break
up all of the cave interior and i think
i'm pretty happy with how this has come
out
i've even added a little walkway he
actually said to me that this purple
wool was where he'd marked out where he
was going to make a walkway so i've just
retextured some of the floor
to be a pathway it was pretty simple and
for some reason and i i don't understand
why
he had this machine here that i still
haven't figured out what this does right
he had he had something where there was
carts that came out here and then they
went literally all the way around the
base
all the way around
on a on a minecart track literally going
and then they ended up
here
and i don't know what his plan was but
it just did a giant loop to end up back
here so i didn't want to mess with it
too much i still sent it on a bit of a
wild goose chase but i just changed it
ever so slightly
so that it comes up up here
and you can kind of see the minecart
from this little vantage point here and
then it ends up going all the way back
down
to where it was so it's the same thing
it's just a bit less intrusive and then
it yeah it ends up coming back down here
where it was meant to be i
what is this machine it makes no sense
so that's kind of what i've done to
improve zf's base texturing roughing up
some of these like bits up here and
adding some boulders and of course the
mushroom blocks along with some patches
of grass i'm not actually sure what else
i can add down here without really
changing
his vision for the base too much and i'm
a little bit worried about that so
because i like i said earlier kind of
want to change back soonish and i'm
going to give a little bit more time for
that to happen but i'm not sure i want
to embark on any more cave building
adventures until that happens
you might remember earlier in the
episode i pointed out that there was
some buildings for sale over here and
maybe some of you already know but the
results have been made and i'm gonna hit
one it's gonna there it is
you know when the world's not loading in
you're in for a surprise okay so
it turns out and i have already checked
scar
sniped me i tried uh
he's given 20 blocks it says 19 but i've
i've unfortunately lost
this building
and i would like to get it back because
i actually have a plot
right here look i don't know why there's
a chicken here that says green
i have nothing to do with chickens but
this here is my plot and i intend on
building something here but i was hoping
that i could get this as well and i
could make barge hq here so maybe i
leave a sign
saying
so i leave a sign saying scott i will
buy for 25 diamond blocks yes and then
lots of question marks actually i need
to tell him that it's me
boom so we'll see what happens with that
hopefully i can buy this off scar
depends what scar
wants to use it for exactly
doesn't scar wait doesn't scar own aqua
town
at qui aqui town how does this makes no
sense at all
let me get this straight for a second
because i might be a bit confused
scar the mayor of the shopping district
who is in charge of all the land
made this sold the land to be dubs who
built this then b-dubs put it up for
auction and then scar bought it back
this is mismanagement of public diamonds
if you ask me
how is it doesn't make much sense to me
but
i'd really like this office how cool
would this be if i could get this space
well
unfortunately we've run out of time for
today and next episode i fully intend on
working out how to swap back so i shall
see you in the next video and of course
thank you so much for watching my videos
and thank you for your patience videos
do take a long time but i've been
working on a big project which is why
this video's taken a little longer than
i anticipated so i shall see you in the
next video which hopefully won't be
quite as long thank you very much for
watching good
bye did you forget to subscribe
pineapple